superyachttimes.com 2019-04-07

# SuperYacht Times

Last Updated: 22 May 2018 

SuperYacht Company B.V., publisher of SuperYachtTimes.com, is committed to protecting your privacy. This Privacy Policy describes how SuperYacht Company and its publications SuperYacht Times and SuperYacht iQ ("Company") collect, use, disclose and transfer the information that you provide to us or that we collect about you when: 

  * you access and use the website of SuperYacht Times at _[ www.superyachttimes.com ](http://www.superyachttimes.com/) _ , SuperYacht iQ at _[www.superyachtiq.com](http://www.superyachtiq.com/) _ __ , or SuperYacht Company at _[ www.superyachtcompany.com ](http://www.superyachtcompany.com/) _ ("Websites") 

  * register for our newsletters 

  * buy our products and services ("Services") 

This Privacy Policy also applies when you visit websites of the Company located on third-party social media websites or communicate with us directly. This Privacy Policy applies regardless of whether you are assessing our websites through a computer, mobile device, tablet or other device. 

For the purposes of this Privacy Policy, the term "Personal Information" means information that identifies an individual or relates to an identifiable individual. 

By using our websites, using Company branded social media pages or by communicating with us directly, you agree to this privacy policy. If you do not accept this privacy policy, you must not use our websites, our services, or Company branded social media pages to communicate with us. 

Other than Company branded social media pages, this Privacy Policy does not apply to any other websites that you may be able to access from the websites (whether through an advertisement, service, or content link) or any websites belonging to our partners, each of which may have data collection, storage, and use practices and policies that differ materially from this Privacy Policy. 

**Personal information that we collect about you**

SuperYacht Company collects data to provide you with the best possible user experience from our products and services. 

We collect information from you when you register on our websites, place an order, subscribe to a newsletter, fill out a form or enter information on our site. 

_A. Visitors_

If you use our websites as a visitor without registering or sending us inquiry information, the only information we collect will be automatic tracking information (please see "Information we automatically collect about you" below). 

_B. Potential Clients_

By potential clients, we mean those individuals or companies who have shared their contact information with us, whether it has been through a form on the website, from information collected at a trade or marketing event, or from those have reached out directly to us. 

For potential clients we may collect information that may personally identify you, including, but not limited to, your contact information including first name, last name, job title, company, address, e-mail address, mobile phone or office phone. We may also collect general information relating to your business objectives, user preferences, and websites and event participation information. 

We use this personal information to manage our relationship with you, including responding to your questions and social media communications and providing you with information about our company and services. 

_C. Clients_

If you purchase services as a client, SuperYacht Company will collect ordering information such as your first name, last name, company, job title, address, e-mail address, mobile phone, or office phone, as well as billing information, such as billing name and address, VAT number, credit card number, and the number of employees and names and emails of employees within the company that will be using the services. We use the ordering and billing information that you provide to place your order. 

_D. Inquirers_

We may also collect information that personally identifies you when you e-mail us or otherwise correspond with us (for example, when you send us e-mail communications, send letters to us or otherwise make inquiries on our websites) or when you use the contact option on our websites. Any such information you provide us will be used to respond to your inquiries. 

_E. Job Applicants and Employees_

When you apply or are hired for a job at SuperYacht Company, we will collect information that you provide us with. We may need to process personal data you provide to further your application in the recruitment process, to process your data to enter into a contract with you, or to comply with our legal obligations (e.g., it is mandatory to check a successful applicant's eligibility to work in the Netherlands before employment starts). We will not share any of the information you provide us with any third parties for marketing purposes. We will only use the information you provide us to contact you to progress your application, to assess your suitability for the role for which you have applied, and to enter into and fulfil our duties to you under a contract. You do not have to provide the information we ask for, but it may affect your application if you decide not to. 

Our management and human resources team will have access to all of this information. This information may include your personal information, including name, contact details, previous experience, education, referees, and answers to questions relevant to the role for which you have applied. 

If your application is unsuccessful, we may keep your personal data on file in case for a period of one (1) year in case there are future employment opportunities for which you may be suited. We will ask for your consent before we keep your data for this purpose and you are free to withdraw your consent at any time. You may also correct your data at any time. 

_F. Market Research_

Occasionally SuperYacht Company may conduct online research in order to gather feedback about our websites and services through email invitations and pop-up surveys. When participating in a survey, we may ask you to submit personal information. This personal information is used for research purposes, and is not used for sales solicitations. When a third party sponsors a survey, aggregate information of the survey results is reported to the sponsor. Personal information collected through market research will be used only by SuperYacht Company and its service providers and contractors and will not be given or sold to a third party without your consent or as otherwise permitted by this Privacy Policy. We will not knowingly accept survey responses from or conduct interviews with any person under the age of 18. 

Although the personal information used in this way will be used by us and assumed to be reliable, no warranty expressed or implied is made regarding the accuracy, adequacy, completeness, reliability or legality of the aggregated uses of the information. In addition to collecting survey responses from our members, cookies may be used to authenticate respondents or to help you pick up where you left off in a survey. If you have cookies disabled you may not be able to participate in some studies. Cookies may be used to connect survey data with our websites' usage characteristics. You will be notified when we would like to use cookies in this way and your consent will be requested for these cookies. 

**INFORMATION WE AUTOMATICALLY COLLECT ABOUT YOU**

Even if you do not register with SuperYacht Company, we collect information about your use of our websites, some of which may be considered personal information. 

_A. Cookies_

Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer's hard drive through your web browser (if you allow) that enables the site's or service provider's systems to recognise your browser and capture and remember certain information. For instance, we use cookies to help us remember and process the items in your shopping cart. They are also used to help us understand your preferences based on previous or current site activity, which enables us to provide you with improved services. We also use cookies to help us compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interaction so that we can offer better site experiences and tools in the future. 

We use cookies to: 

  * Help remember and process the items in the shopping cart. 

  * Understand and save users' preferences for future visits. 

  * Keep track of advertisements. 

  * Compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interactions in order to offer better site experiences and tools in the future. We may also use trusted third-party services that track this information on our behalf. 

You can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies. You do this through your browser settings. Since every browser is a little different, look at your browser's Help Menu to learn the correct way to modify your cookies. 

If you turn cookies off, some of the features that make your site experience more efficient may not function properly. 

_B. Web Beacons_

We (or third parties with whom we contract) may use "web beacons" alone or in conjunction with cookies to collect anonymous information about your use of our websites and the websites of selected sponsors and advertisers, and your use of emails, special promotions or newsletters we send to you. Web beacons are tiny graphic image files embedded in a web page or email that provide a presence on the web page or email and send back to its home server information from the user's browser. The information collected by web beacons allows us to statistically monitor how many people are using our websites and selected sponsors' and advertisers' sites and opening our emails, and may be used to track your activity outside of our websites or those of our sponsors'. We do not link non-personal information from web beacons to personal information without your permission. 

_C. Traffic Data_

We automatically track and collect the following categories of information when you visit our website: (1) Internet Protocol (IP) addresses; (2) domain servers; (3) computer, device and connection information, such as browser type and version, operating system, mobile platform and unique device identifier (UDID) and other technical identifiers; (4) Uniform Resource Locator (URL) click stream data, including date and time stamp, referring and exit URLs, search terms you used and pages you visited or search for on the Service; (5) for location-aware services, the region, city or town where your device is located in order to provide you with more relevant content for where you are in the world; (5) referring source which may have sent you to the website; and (6) other information associated with the interaction of your browser and the website. If you are using a mobile or other device to visit the website, we may collect hardware information related to the device about you. 

**HOW WE USE YOUR INFORMATION**

We may use the personal information that we collect from you when you register, make a purchase, sign up for our newsletter, respond to a survey or marketing communication, surf the website, or use certain other site features in the following ways: 

  * To personalise your experience and to allow us to deliver the type of content and product offerings in which you are most interested. 

  * To improve our website in order to better serve you. 

  * To allow us to better service you in responding to your customer service requests. 

  * To quickly process your transactions. 

  * To communicate with your and to personalise our communications with you. 

  * To send periodic emails regarding your order or other products and services. 

  * SuperYacht Company may use your data to select and deliver some of the advertisements you see on our websites. 

  * SuperYacht Company may share your data with third parties like Facebook and LinkedIn to enable us to deliver advertisements to you relating to services of SuperYacht Company that you have previously engaged with. 

As a practical matter, your contact and financial information will be stored in our CRM tools, which are hosted in the United States but always subject to the requirements of applicable data protection laws and this Privacy Policy. By registering with us, using the websites or providing your personal information to us, you consent to that transfer. 

**HOW WE PROTECT YOUR INFORMATION**

Our websites are scanned on a regular basis for security holes and known vulnerabilities in order to make your visit to our site as safe as possible. We use regular malware scanning. Your personal information is contained behind secured networks and is only accessible by a limited number of persons who have special access rights to such systems, and are required to keep the information confidential. In addition, all sensitive/credit information you supply is encrypted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology. 

We implement a variety of security measures when a user places an order, enters, submits, or accesses their information to maintain the safety of your personal information. 

All transactions are processed through a gateway provider and are not stored or processed on our servers. 

We strive to protect your personal information, however, SuperYacht Company cannot ensure and does not warrant the security of the information you transmit to us. If you have reason to believe that your account with us has been compromised or is not secure, please notify us of the problem immediately by contacting us. 

**DATA INTEGRITY**

SuperYacht Company will use personal data only in ways that are compatible with the purposes for which it was collected, authorised by this Privacy Policy, or authorised by you. You are responsible with providing us with accurate information. You may contact us for ensuring the accuracy of your personal data. 

**RETENTION PERIOD**

SuperYacht Company will retain personal data about you for the period reasonably necessary to fulfil the purposes described in this Privacy Policy and consistent with its retention policy and as required or permitted by law. 

**THIRD-PARTY DISCLOSURE**

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information unless we provide users with advance notice. This does not include website hosting partners and other parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or serving our users, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. We may also release information when its release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others' rights, property or safety. 

However, non-personally identifiable visitor information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses. 

We reserve the right to disclose your personally identifiable information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights or property, to mitigate our liability in an actual or potential lawsuit, to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our websites, to enforce this Privacy Policy or any other agreement in place between you and SuperYacht Company, or to investigate and prevent unauthorised transactions or other illegal activities. 

**THIRD-PARTY LINKS**

The websites may contain links to third party websites to which SuperYacht Company has no affiliation. SuperYacht Company does not share your personal information with those websites and is not responsible for their privacy practices. Some websites may have the look and feel of our websites. Please be aware that you may be on a different site and that this Privacy Policy only covers our websites. If you access other sites using the links provided, the operators of these websites may have their own privacy policies. 

**WHO WE SHARE YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION WITH**

_A. Google_

Google's advertising requirements can be summed up by Google's Advertising Principles. They are put in place to provide a positive experience for users. https://support.google.com/adwordspolicy/answer/1316548?hl=en We use Google AdSense Advertising on our website. 

Google, as a third-party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on our site. Google's use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to our users based on previous visits to our site and other sites on the Internet. Users may opt-out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google Ad and Content Network privacy policy. 

We have implemented the following: 

  * DoubleClick Platform Integration 

We, along with third-party vendors such as Google use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookies) and third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie) or other third-party identifiers together to compile data regarding user interactions with ad impressions and other ad service functions as they relate to our website. 

Users can set preferences for how Google advertises to you using the Google Ad Settings page. Alternatively, you can opt out by visiting the Network Advertising Initiative Opt Out page or by using the Google Analytics Opt Out Browser add on. 

_Facebook_

SuperYacht Company uses Facebook advertising services to promote our services to visitors of our websites. 

_LinkedIn_

SuperYacht Company uses LinkedIn advertising services to promote our services to visitors of our websites. 

**HOW DO OUR WEBSITES HANDLE DO NOT TRACK SIGNALS?**

We honour Do Not Track signals and we do not track, plant cookies, or use advertising when a Do Not Track (DNT) browser mechanism is in place. 

**DO OUR WEBSITES ALLOW THIRD-PARTY BEHAVIORAL TRACKING?**

It's also important to note that we allow third-party behavioural tracking 

**HOW YOU CAN ACCESS, CHANGE OR SUPPRESS YOUR PERSONAL DATA**

If you would like to review, correct, update, suppress, delete or otherwise limit our use of your personal data that has been provided to us, you may make a request by contacting us using the contact information for SuperYacht Company below. For your protection, we may need to verify the request is valid. We will try to comply with your request as soon as reasonably practicable and consistent with applicable law. 

If you completely delete all such information, your account may become deactivated. Please note that we may need to retain certain information for recordkeeping purposes and/or to complete any transactions that are pending. 

**CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY**

We reserve the right, at any time, to add to, change, update, or modify this Privacy Policy so please review it frequently. In all cases, the use of information we collect is subject to the Privacy Policy in effect at the time such information is collected. If you do not agree with any changes or modifications to the Privacy Policy, please do not continue using our websites. You will be deemed to have consented to any modification of the Privacy Policy when you use the websites after the effective date of the modification. 

**CONTACT INFORMATION**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, or your dealings with SuperYacht Company and our websites, or want to request access or changes to our handling of your data, or to lodge a complaint, please contact us. 

**SuperYacht Company B.V.**

Singel 260 

Amsterdam, NH 1016 AB 

The Netherlands 

_[info@superyachttimes.com](mailto:info@superyachttimes.com) _
